Today we're going to talk about how you
can build anything with AI, but people
are going to need to figure out
distribution. How do you actually get
customers to the thing that you're vibe
coding? I believe that the wealthiest
people will be marketers over the next
10 years. But every YouTube tutorial is
telling you how to vibe code. So today,
by the end of this episode, you're going
to have seven really straightforward
things that you can do this week.
frameworks, ideas, alpha that's working
right now, uh, so that you can actually
build a software company, a SAS, an
agent company that actually gets
customers. So, I'm going to explain how
to do it. By the end of this, you're
going to get your creative juices
flowing. I needed to make this episode.
I really needed to make this episode.
I'm actually recording at night and you
know I tweeted this that you know people
need to figure out distribution you know
and it hurts me that people are you know
don't have the ideas around it. So like
and comment if you want me to do more
episodes on this. Let's get right into
it.
>> So I believe that there's this great
flip happening. you know, I moved to
Silicon Valley um in 2014
and uh when I moved it was all about
engineers as number one. I actually
studied computer science in university
because I was like engineers are number
one on the hierarchy, right? And then it
became product uh and then marketing as
at the bottom like literally the
laughingtock of Silicon Valley were
marketing people. Now today I believe
that you know because of AI distribution
people who understand distribution how
to get customers is you know you're at
the top of the list then it's product
people and then it's developers. Um this
is
you know a big deal because I actually
think that not a lot of people
understand distribution. They don't
understand brand. They don't understand
advertising. They don't understand
content. Um, but I think that, you know,
if you can, you know, if you do
understand it, you are at an unfair
advantage. Um, you know, there's 200,000
new vibe coding projects being created
every single day on Lovable. Um, how
many people are actually seeing those
products? Probably not a lot. Um, Peter
Levelvels has $3 million plus of
revenue. He has zero employees. The
reason why he's been able to uh you know
get so much revenue as a one-person
business is he's got 750,000 plus
followers I think and also he's got
great SEO. I mean if you look at some of
the stuff that he works on you know
Nomad List for example
a lot of the tools
uh like these could be you know copied
quite quickly. Um you know it's it's
essentially a directory. I've done
episodes and tours on how to vibe code
directories before, you know, but he's
he's obviously got good data and data is
part of that, but it's also largely he's
got an audience, he's got trust, and
he's built good SEO.
We'll talk more about that in this
episode. So the big trap uh that I think
a lot of founders and builders do is
they vibe code something, you know, once
they've built the product, they've got
this great idea. Um then they're just
going to try marketing things, but it's
just silence. So then they're going to
build more features and they're going to
launch again and more silence. So they
basically are just thinking about how do
I build a really good product? Um and if
you build it, they will come. But they
don't come. What smart builders do is
they start with the distribution. So
they'll grow an audience uh to maybe a
thousand people. They ask that audience
what they need. Uh and then they go and
build it in a weekend, 24 hours, 72
hours, a few days. Um and then that
audience is shocked that wow you built
the thing that I wanted. And then you
launch it to a warm audience. You
iterate with real users and you start
making money. So it's distribution
first, product second. Always. You know
the example of Peter Levelvels. I think
I you know I think he's tweeted 125,000
times in the last like eight years. You
know he's he's put in the consistency
and the work to actually go and build
that audience and he's been iterating
with users and customers you know with
them. So let's get into the actual
tactics. Uh strategy one is going to be
about using an MCP server as your sales
team. So, you know, if you're listen if
you're listening to Startup Ideas
podcast, you probably know what an MCP
is. Um, but you can think of it as
basically like an uh an app. Um, you
know, the example I I'll use here is,
you know, plugins in OpenAI. You use the
o the MCP protocol. So, you can just be
like at Google Drive, find the right
drive, then summarize a doc and update a
sheet or edit a slides deck. So, there's
this massive opportunity to build MCP
servers as your sales team. How does it
work? Well, a user asks an a the AI. It
could be, you know, Claude, it could be
Chad GBT
as a question. The AI discovers your MCP
server and AI returns uh you know your
product and the user gets value from it.
So there's zero CAC. The AI assistant
basically becomes your sales teams. And
I have friends who are you know I'm
actually incubating uh some things you
know around here. And actually if you
look at ideabrowser.com
you know we we've been doing some MCP
stuff we also have a lot of friends who
just you know in in for example in the
fintech space you know 150 plus
installations in 30 days $0 ad spend for
something that he vibe coded uh quite
quickly. So I believe that building an
MCP server in 2026 is in a lot of ways
building like kind of building for
mobile in 2010. there's just a lot of
opportunities to show up in LLMs in
these connections plugins or MCP
servers. So, how can you start uh this
week? And and by the way, I realize that
this, you know, an MPC an MCP server,
it's not for everyone, right? If you're
building a boring business, maybe that's
not for you or, you know, even some
software businesses might might not be
for you. But for some people, for SAS,
you know, if you want to get started
this week, um what can you do? Identify
what question your product answers.
That's the first thing you're going to
want to do. Number two, you're going to
want to build an MCP server that returns
that data. You can vibe the code that
realistically in 24 hours or less.
You're going to want to publish that to
MCP registries, uh, Smithery, MCPT, Open
Tools, and then every AI assistant that
connects to your server is now selling
for you 24/7. So, that's a bet that
you're going to make. Um, and that's
strategy number one. Let's get to
strategy number two. Strategy number two
is programmatic SEO. So, it's how can
you create 10,000 pages SEO pages in 48
hours. So, you're going to want to look
at, you know, a keyword a keyword
pattern pattern. Best X for Y. So, best
uh CRM for dentists, for example. Then,
you're going to want to do uh look at uh
data sets. So, you're going to want to I
actually did a whole episode on
firecrawl recently, a tutorial on how to
use it. Um, so you're going to want to
but basically what does that do if you
haven't seen that? It basically goes and
scrapes and gets you clean structured
data. Uh, so that you can actually, you
know, provide value in your in your
pages. Uh, then you're going to want to
do use a page template, Nex.js. You can
use cloud code or something to actually
go and build this. Uh, then you're going
to want to actually create AI content.
And then you're going to go and create
10,000 pages. Now, I know there's a big
gap. I can see the comment right in the
comment section right now. It's okay.
Oh, you're just going to press one
button and then just automatically
create 10,000 pages. Uh well, no, of
course not because you you know, you you
do need to make sure that the content is
good and doesn't feel like AI. So,
there's going to be a lot of
optimizations that you're going to have
to do to actually get it so it doesn't
feel like AI. But once you get it to
there, I mean, you can start with just a
few pages and once you get it to there,
then you can start scaling to to more
pages. Um, you know, the math is is
pretty simple. If you end up creating,
you know, 10,000 pages and each page
gets 30 visits a month, which, you know,
it's not a lot of visits, right? Um,
that could go up to, you know, 300,000
monthly visitors. If you convert at 2%,
that's 6,000 conversions a month. Maybe
that's $10 each. and then all of a
sudden you're making $60,000 a month
from pages you built once. Now those 30
visits a month that's not going to
happen overnight. Um SEO does take some
time to compound and but like think
about it directionally, right?
Directionally the idea is build a lot of
pages, get really good at creating AI
content, get structured data that's ex
that's high quality um and uh and and
and rinse repeat. So, how can I actually
start this this week? If this is
something that's interesting to you, how
can I go and start this this week? Well,
you're going to want to pick a keyword
pattern. So, like the product type for
niche or service in city um like for
example the CRM for dentist or um you
know uh roofing in Miami. You're going
to want to build your data set. So,
you're going to want to scrape with
firecrawl or you can use existing
databases. You can create a template in
your framework like you know nest
next.js JS, Web Flow, WordPress doesn't,
you know, just stick with the thing that
you're going to use. And then you're
going to want to use AI to generate
unique content per page. So, not just
variable swaps, actual paragraphs,
highquality stuff. Um, and you know, you
also might want to have a human in the
loop to actually edit and look at some
of this content. Publish a 100 pages as
an MVP, monitor indexation, and then
that's when you can go ahead and scale.
So, that's number two. I think that's
applicable to really anyone. doesn't
make a difference if you're building a
service, a SAS, an app, you've got a
boring business, you got an agency,
programmatic SEO is still under tap.
Strategy number three, uh three on seven
is doing a free tool as a top of the
funnel uh for your top of the funnel.
So, the tool is your marketing. Um, you
know, the example I would use is, uh,
Href for for a while has had this
backlink check, uh, checker. So, you
know, you you put in your domain, for
example, gregisenberg.com.
It's going to see what are the different
backlinks, like who's uh connected to
me, uh, what links are connected to me.
Um, and, you know, is high quality and
stuff like that. And, you know, but the
the reality is it gives you a taste of
their full product. So if I want more, I
have to go and spend hundreds of dollars
or thousands of dollars a month with
Hrefs. So they kind of hook you in
through that. So you know, step one is
building a free tool. It could be a
grader, it can be an analyzer, it can be
a calculator. Uh step two is the user
gets instant value. So you know, your
site scores 43 on 100. Um, generally
what you want to do is obviously grab
their data in some capacity, you know,
text message, email in order to get
access that. Uh, step three is the user
shares their score. So, that's going to
help this thing go viral. Uh, social
proof, back back links. Um, and then
step four is more users are going to
discover it. So, you've got this organic
viral loop. And step five is upsell to a
paid product. So, you want to fix these
issues? Well, we've got the product for
you. Now this uh strategy has been
around for for a while, right? Um you
know, but why is it different? Well, now
it's different because you can use cloud
code uh to go and actually build these
free tools, right? It's now like not
crazy to build a free tool a week,
whereas in the past these things would
have taken you months. So you can vibe
code a free tool in a day, ship it by
lunch, and it markets itself forever.
So, uh, I really like this one. This is
something that I'm doing in all my
businesses as much as possible. Um, and
if you want to get started this week, I
would just say, uh, you know, I would
ask, uh, you know, your LLM of choice to
be like, here's what I'm working on, and
give me 10 ideas for free tools that can
act as my top of the funnel. And that's,
you know, you're going to have your 10
tools. You can prioritize the best poss
ones that you think are the best. You
can even ask your audience, hey, what
would be more interesting? This or that?
Um, get them involved and then go and
build it and then just, you know, we we
think of uh when you do social media,
you think of like an editorial calendar,
a content calendar, but no one really
thinks about like a free tool calendar.
And I really do believe the tool is the
marketing. This is working. Don't know
why more people aren't doing it. Um, but
strategy number three, one of my faves.
Strategy number four, answer engine
optimization. So you want to be the
source that AI sites. So the old way of,
you know, getting seen obviously was
SEO. You just wanted to get, you know,
on on Google page one. You do 30,000word
blog posts. You're doing backlink
building, keyword stuffing. Oh my god.
Um click through your site. You know,
I'm just having flashbacks of all of
doing all this stuff. Um it's there's
still opportunity in SEO. I mean we
talked about it today but it's declining
um and zeroclick searches are growing
right so um if AEO is in 2026 is where
SEO was in 2010 first movers will own
these niches for years so uh the idea is
answer engine optimization how do we get
cited by chat GBT and perplexity you
know structured direct answers you can
do an FAQ format schema markup
comparison and tables that AI can parse
so that you know that way uh yeah you're
getting seen a little more. Um and then
AI AI is going to send users to your
product. So um yeah I think it was Peter
Levelvels actually uh I believe that he
said like his AI referrals jumped from
4% to 20% in 1 month. I think that it's
only going to increase for you know
across the board on e-commerce SAS apps
you you name it. So, um, it's worth kind
of, uh, exploring. It's worth exploring.
So, okay, great. You know, you probably
already knew this. Obviously, you know,
you want to be seen in Perplexia or Chat
GBT, but how do you, how can you start
this this week? Well, Google the top
step one is to Google the top 20
questions your customer asks.
And you're going to step two, write the
definitive structured answers for each.
So, I'm not talking about 3,000word
fluff. I'm talking about clear, direct,
citation worthy. It's all about getting
citation worthy content. Then you're
going to add step three, add schema
markup and FAQ blocks. Step four, you're
going to want to publish on a domain
with authority or build authority
through the other strategies. Um,
obviously it's bet, you know, why a
Peter Levels,
you know, could could get his SEO and
AEO up quickly, more quicker than the
average person listening to this is
because a lot of his domains have built
authority over time. So, uh, you know,
there's no better time. Start building
that authority today. And then lastly,
monitor your perplexity and chat GBT
citations. You can use tools like
Otterly, there's profound, there's
manual testing. Um but the important
thing here is that you're just getting
started. So get started this week um on
AEO. Strategy number five is how can you
make your outputs of your product
sharable? So we all know you know the
end of year December Spotify wrapped. Um
they get 100 million shares every
December of that thing. It's absolutely
crazy. Um everyone wants to share it.
Your mother wants to share it. Your
sister wants to share it. Your kids want
to share it. Everyone is sharing it,
laughing about it. It says it says about
something about your identity, who you
are. So what is that for you, right? So
what is the free distribution output
sharable thing that you can be creating?
You know, the way I the way I the way I
have it in my head at least is, you
know, ask what does my user want to brag
about and then make that thing beautiful
and sharable. Uh for GitHub, they've got
the contribution graph. Um, and then you
see like devs bragging about sharing
those green squares on Twitter. Uh,
Stripe Atlas, which allows you to create
companies. You know, the artifact there
is the incorporation milestone. Founders
tweet, uh, I just I just incorporated or
it's been 5 years since uh, I
incorporated. Uh, here's my, you know,
my anniversary post lessons learned.
Duolingo perhaps you know one of the
most famous uh examples daily streak
count and then uh you know users are
bragging about 365day streaks I don't
know if Snapchat was before them I think
they were um but like I think yeah I
think that was an original Snapchat
thing too right um I like to look at
like how social products like what are
social products doing um because you can
actually take a lot of that thinking
that psychology and bring that into
whatever it is you're doing so your
product. What is the artifact that
you're going to create? What is the
viral artifact that you're going to
create? Um, what do your users want to
brag about? So, if we want to get
started this week, what are we going to
what do we need? Step one, we're going
to have to identify the output or
milestone your user would screenshot and
share. Step two, let's make it
beautiful. Let's make it sharable. Let's
make it branded. Your logo actually
should be subtle but present. I've seen
some examples of artifacts that the logo
is super big and it just no one wants to
share someone else's logo. It should be
it should feel uh it's about you. Step
three is you're going to want to add a
share button that prefills the post with
the artifact. Step four, every share is
free impressions to your exact target
audience. So that's a huge win. Um the
user is doing your marketing because
they're bragging about themselves. Uh
people are going to say well these are
you know mostly consumer uh examples
will this work in B2B
um or you know yeah B2B yes you know at
the end of the day B2B are people too
there's things that these you know
people want to share maybe they're
sharing it within Slack maybe they're
sharing it within Microsoft Teams but
just think about what is something that
they are willing to share uh with your
with the group that you ultimately want
more of. So that is strategy number
five. Strategy number six. So you know
me, you know, I think audiences are
really important. Um, sometimes, you
know, it's just hard to build an
audience. Listen, a lot of times it's
hard to build the audience more more
often than not. Uh, it takes it takes
sometimes years. It requires daily
content. Uh, there's no guarantee it
works too, right? Sometimes you just it
doesn't work. Um, and then it it's
tough, right? Because you have zero
subscribers on day one. So, uh, what if
you just acquired a niche newsletter
instead of building from zero? So, this
is something a lot of people don't think
about, but you can go and like buy a
10,000 subscriber newsletter for $5 to
$20,000. You inherit that trust from day
one. You plug in your product
immediately, and then you can repeat
that across niches. Um,
if you have a product that you believe
in and you understand the LTV, this just
might make sense for you. Uh, so,
and a lot of these uh, smaller
newsletters, like they're not really
monetizing that well, so they might be
like stoked to get a $10,000 offer from
you. So, if we want to just get this
started this week, uh I would go to
deuce.com,
uh which is like a, you know, listing of
selling newsletters, newsletter
investor, or just search your niche
newsletter on Twitter or Substack and
just try to find these newsletters.
That's step one. Step two is you
probably want to look at the 5,000 to
50,000 subscriber in your target niche.
You obviously don't want to buy
something so big in the beginning. Uh,
but I mean, listen, if you have the
money and you really do understand the
LTV, maybe you do. Um, it's all about
confidence. Uh, how much confidence that
you have. Uh, step three is DM the
owner. Have you ever thought about
selling? Uh, you'd be surprised how many
people would say, uh, would take the
call. Um, next step is, you know, a lot
of these a lot of these folks, as I
mentioned, are not really making that
much money. Maybe they're making 0 to
$500 a month, and they would be open to
a fair offer. uh you know five to 10 to
15 to $20,000 and then all of a sudden
you own a direct channel to your exact
audience and more importantly it's not a
social media account that could be taken
away from you at at any point. This is a
yeah a direct line uh that you can go
and put links to and if you want to put
your product in there and say come buy
my product you know it's going to get
seen unlike places uh like social media
that could suppress your reach over
time. So I think this is something that
not a lot of people think of so I
definitely wanted to throw it throw it
in there. Um the last strategy is uh
thinking about uh AI building an AI
content repurposing engine. So
the way I think about it is this. You
can think about uh creating one, you
know, hero or pillar piece of content.
That could be a podcast episode, a
YouTube video, a long blog post, an
essay. Um, and that one piece of content
ends up becoming
uh a lot more. You know, it could be 50,
75, you know, 20, depends how much you
want to get out of it. So, you can
actually use AI to take that pillar
content, turn it into five to 10, you
know, tweets, three to five LinkedIn
posts, two to three short form videos,
one newsletter. And the short form
videos would be using like a reotion
uh skill uh on something like a cloud
code um you know a newsletter edition a
blog post 5 to 10 quote graphics that
you can use creative LLMs go and create
for you email sequences and a lot of
this stuff can actually you know for the
people into openclaw they can go and
automate with openclaw you can also use
um just cloud dispatch and and I think
uh you know claude co-work um perplexity
computer, any of these to go and
automate some some of this stuff for
you. The big the big idea here is you
get one thing that'll equal a bunch of
different contents and that gives you
way more touch points across uh multiple
platforms. Um so if you want to get that
started this week, um you know, I I I
would suggest just starting recording
like one 30 minute piece of content. It
could be a podcast, could be a video, or
just a voice memo. it's way harder to
actually go and write a uh 3,000word
essay on something. And I just find if
you just voice memo something or you do
a podcast uh can be like it could also
just be an internal podcast or just a
like literally a video of you that you
don't end up putting out and that like
the actual value is in the you know the
repurposing that AI is going to do. Uh
you're going to want to transcribe it.
You can drop the translation into cloud.
turn this into five tweet threads, three
LinkedIn posts, and one newsletter. Um,
obviously it needs to be set up
properly. Obviously,
uh, you know,
there's you you're going to get slop by
default, so you have to optimize to not
slop. And a part of that is having a
really good brand and reference images.
A part of that is, you know, setting
routines. So, it's going, you know, and
researching, you know, different topics
and adding to what you have. Part of it
is uh
part of it is knowing what skills and
having those skills you know
implemented. Um but you know you can get
started by just by just getting started
and then schedule across platforms. Um
if you do this every week I think in 3
months you'll have more content than
your competitors. You know your
competitors are not putting out this
amount of of amount of content. They
just really aren't. And where we are
with content just, you know, in 2026 is
because of for you pages. Um, you know,
you c you never know when you can go
viral in your niche. Um, and you don't
need a lot of followers to start. You
just need a lot of shots on net. So,
this is kind of like a shots on net
strategy. And I don't know why more
people aren't, you know, building this
out. So those are the seven strategies,
growth strategies that, you know, I
think are interesting and that I think,
you know, I would pay attention to if I
was vibe coding something, if I wanted
to build a business, if I wanted
customers to that business, if I wanted
to build a growth engine. Um, code used
to be the moat. I think by now, maybe by
the end of this, you you understand that
uh distribution is the new moat, right?
It's the most important thing is
distribution. you know it's scarce right
AI can't build it product is really
important but it you know in lots of
ways it is commoditized and code is
fully commoditized so I've given you
seven distribution weapons
uh just to summarize I've given you MCP
servers so let AI sell for you I've
given you programmatic SEO 10,000 pages
in a weekend I've given you free tool
the tool is your marketing I've given
you answer engine optimization be the
source AI I sites. I've given you viral
artifacts, make your output sharable.
I've given you buy a newsletter, acquire
the audience, and I've given you AI
repurposing engine, one pillar, and
seven channels. So, pick two of them.
Start this week. Don't just vibe code.
Um, I want to see you get customers,
make money, grow from there, reinvest,
have fun. Um, and I'm h, you know, I
wanted to do this because, like I said,
I want I want I don't want you just to
to be to be, you know, vibe coding stuff
and no one's seeing it. And I think
there's too many people doing that. Um,
so if this is interesting, like I said,
let me know and I can do more of these.
I have tons of strategies that I use. I
can go deeper in the future. Um, I'm
here to help you. um the Startup Ideas
podcast like I I I am here to help you
get uh increase your odds of success
with good ideas, growth tactics, startup
ideas. So, you know, please share this
with a friend, let me know what you
think, and I'll see you on the next
episode. Happy building.